Guide to the City of Portland photographs collection. circa 1925-1945
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
City of Portland photographs collection
circa 1925-1945
Oregon Historical Society Research Library 1200 SW Park Avenue Portland, Oregon 97205 Phone: 503-306-5240 Fax: 503-219-2040 E-mail: libreference@ohs.org
Org. Lot 50
Portland (Or.).
3 cubic feet 7 document cases
Photographs of Portland, Oregon, taken by photographers employed by the City of Portland. Includes street scenes, neighborhoods, businesses, thoroughfares, the harbor, and maps of the city.
Original negatives of these photographs are housed in the City of Portland Archives and Records Center.
Historical Note
Portland, Oregon, began as a clearing on the west bank of the Willamette River in 1844. The new city was incorporated in 1851 and prospered because of its advantageous location near the confluence of the Willamette and Columbia Rivers, among other factors. Its growth was spurred by flourishing agriculture in the Willamette Valley, the California gold rush, the Indian wars of the 1850s, and gold discoveries in eastern Oregon and Idaho in the 1860s. By the Civil War, Portland was the principal metropolis of the Pacific Northwest with a population of around 3000. The arrival of the Northern Pacific and Union Pacific railroads in 1883 and 1884 contributed to a new boom in prosperity, and in 1891 the city annexed the municipalities of Albina and East Portland on the east side of the Willamette. Residential growth was most dramatic in the eastern districts after 1900, and expansion was especially rapid after the Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition in 1905. By 1910 Portland's population was over 207,000, and it continued its rapid growth up to the 1930s.
The collection consists of images taken throughout Portland, Oregon, with emphasis on the downtown and eastern portions of the city. Included are street scenes, thoroughfares, business establishments, and neighborhood views. The bulk of the images appear to date from the late 1920s and early 1930s. Many may have been created in relation to specific city projects, such as street paving, sewer installation, and improvement of blighted neighborhoods. Visible in many of the photographs from the early 1930s is a man holding a number -- probably a city employee engaged in a particular project. In general, the photographs provide detailed documentation of the city's built environment, much of which is still extant.
The collection is arranged by subjects, with files numbered to correspond to the Oregon Historical Society's Photograph Files. Neighborhood numbering corresponds to the system used by the Oregon Historical Society (e.g., "SW1, NW4, etc.).
Negatives used to create these prints are housed in the City of Portland Archives and Records Center.
The collection is open to the public.
Original negatives were obtained from the City of Portland; prints in this collection were made by the Oregon Historical Society.
Negatives for these images are held by the City of Portland Archives and Records Center, Portland, Oregon.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Portland (Or.).
Portland (Or.)--Photographs.; Portland (Or.)--Business enterprises--Photographs.
Automobiles--Oregon--Portland--Photographs.; Architecture--Oregon--Portland--Photographs.
Portland; Photographs; City and Town Life
Photographs
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- City of Portland Photographs Collection
  - Miscellaneous--Transportation--Oregon Electric, 1921 (Folder 891-C-7)
    Includes downtown streets and trolley tracks.
  - Urban decay, 1934-1944 (Folder 1500-A)
    Images of abandoned houses.
  - Cabins, etc., 1941 (Folder 1501)
    Includes images from Sullivan's Gulch
  - General Views, 1970 (Folder 1514)
    Aerial photographs of Portland
  - Waterfront, 1920-1939 (Folder 1534)
    Includes images of sea walls and docks
  - Waterfront, 1940 (Folder 1535)
    Includes aerial photograph of the Public Market Building
  - Streets-NW/SW Front Ave., 1920-1939 (Folder 1544)
  - Streets- NW/SW Front Ave., 1940-1959 (Folder 1545)
    Images of SW Front Ave widening project
  - Streets-NW/SW Front Ave., Undated (Folder 1546)
    Includes images of rowhouses
  - Streets-NW/SW 2nd Ave., Undated (Folder 1565)
    Images of public restrooms and sidewalks
  - Streets-NW/SW 3rd Ave 1910-1929, 1906-1923 (Folder 1573)
    Includes images of newspaper vendor stand, trolley tracks and trolley lines
  - Streets-NW/SW 4th Ave., 1906-1937 (Folder 1582)
  - Streets-NW/SW 5th Ave., 1928 (Folder 1586)
    Images of downtown streets at night
  - Streets-NW/SW, 1906-1936 (Folder 1587)
    Includes images of Chapman Square, downtown streetcar in motion
  - Streets-NW/SW 6th Ave., Undated (Folder 1592)
    Includes overhead image of pedestrians at crowsswalk
  - Streets-NW/SW Broadway (7th Ave), 1906-1936 (Folder 1597)
    Includes images of downtown streets at night
  - Streets-NW/SW Park (8th 9th Ave), 1923 (Folder 1601)
    Street signs for Morrison St., Park St., and West Park St.
  - Streets-NW/SW Park (8th 9th Ave), 1936-1940 (Folder 1602)
    Includes images of roadwork involving trolley tracks, dowtown apartment building facades
  - Streets-NW/SW 10th Ave., Undated (Folder 1605)
  - Streets-NW/SW 11th Ave, 1906-1939 (Folder 1606)
    Includes images of residential basement, residential and downtown streets
  - Streets-NW/SW 12th Ave., Undated (Folder 1607)
    Trolley tracks at NW 12th and Lovejoy
  - Streets-NW/SW 14th Ave, 1928-1937 (Folder 1609)
    Includes images of roadwork; man posing with car by roadside
  - Streets-NW/SW 15th Ave, Undated (Folder 1610)
    SW 15th and Salmon
  - Streets-NW/SW 16th Ave, 1937 (Folder 1611)
    Images of man replacing street sign at NW 16th and Glisan
  - Streets Miscellaneous-East Side, Undated (Folder 1619)
    Includes images of construction on NE Broadway and Larrabee, images of Prescott Street, 42nd Ave and N. Willamette Boulevard, pedestrian subway at N. Interstate and Ainsworth, mudslides on Interstate Ave, images of SE Division, Belmont St and SE 81st Ave
  - Streets--Miscellaneous-West Side, Undated (Folder 1619)
    Includes mudslides on SW Fairview, Melinda Ave and Barbur Boulevard, series titled "Entering Portland", Barbur Blvd. construction, images of St.Helen's Road, railroad yards in Northwest Portland
  - Streets-W. Burnside, 1906-1938 (Folder 1620)
    Includes trolley tracks and overhead lines, mudslide on Hermosa St., retaining wall construction, residential and downtown streets, images of horse drawn carts
  - Streets-E. Burnside, Undated (Folder 1620-A)
    Includes residential streets and vacant lots
  - Streets-SW Pine St., 1936 (Folder 1623)
    SW Broadway and SW Pine
  - Streets-SW Stark St., 1927-1936 (Folder 1625)
  - Streets-SW Washington St., 1913-1934 (Folder 1627)
    Includes image of condemned lot
  - Streets-SW Alder St., Undated (Folder 1629)
    Includes Alder Street dock, overhead view of pedestrians at crosswalk
  - Streets-SW Morrison St., 1927 (Folder 1631)
    Includes image of Meier and Frank Building
  - Streets-SW Yamhill St., Undated (Folder 1633)
    Includes empty lot at Yamhill and 3rd Avenue, house at SW Yamhill and St.Clair
  - Streets-SW Salmon St, Undated (Folder 1635)
    Street view at SW Salmon near 18th
  - Streets-SW Main St., 1936 (Folder 1636)
    Street view at SW 6th and Main St
  - Streets-SW Madison St, 1936 (Folder 1637)
    Street view at SW 6th and Madison
  - Streets-SW Jefferson, 1906-1934 (Folder 1638)
    Includes street view at SW Jefferson up Vista Blvd., overhead view of SW Jefferson St.
  - SW Neighborhoods- Miscellaneous [including Fulton (SW 10)], 1934-1940 (Folder 1650)
    Includes images of residential houses on SW Madison St., condemned lots on SW Madison, ditch digging on SW Taylors Ferry Road
  - SW Neighborhoods-Council Crest (SW 8), 1937-1939 (Folder 1653)
    Includes road work on Council Crest Park Road, residential house at SW Beaverton Ave and SW Chehalem Ave.
  - SW Neighborhoods-Portland Heights (SW 4, SW 5, SW 6), 1938-1939 (Folder 1656)
    Includes Marquam Gulch fill, SW Ford Street Dr., mudslide at SW 15th and Mrytle
  - SW Neighborhoods-South Portland (SW 3, SW 7), 1933-1941 (Folder 1657)
    Includes houses along Barbur Blvd., images of SW Front Ave., railroad bridge near SW 3rd Ave., images of the Marquam Gulch fill, the Boulevard Tavern, roadwork crews on SW Barbur and Whitaker, garage and tire shop on SW 3rd and Arthur, pipe lines on SW Seymour and Macadam
  - NW Neighborhoods-Miscellaneous, 1940 (Folder 1660)
  - NW Neighborhoods- West Burnside (NW 1, NW 2), 1928-1942 (Folder 1661)
    Includes railroad tracks and lines at NW 13th and Lovejoy, train cars unloading at NW 10th and Yeon, man posing with car at NW 14th and Lovejoy
  - NW Neighborhoods- Kings Heights-Westover (NW 4), 1933-1938 (Folder 1663)
    Includes mudslide above Maywood Dr., mudslide on Melinda Ave
  - NW Neighborhoods- Linnton (NW 7), 1934-1936 (Folder 1664)
    Includes railroad yards, mudslide on NW St.Helen's road, Gasco building on St.Helen's Road
  - NW Neighborhoods-NW Industrial (NW 6), 1938-1942 (Folder 1665)
    Includes Guild's Lake Area, trains and railroad tracks
  - NW Neighborhoods-Willamette Heights-Forest Park (NW 5), 1934-1935 (Folder 1667)
    Includes backyard gazebo on NW Thurman St.
  - NW Neighborhoods- Slabtown (NW 3), 1930 (Folder 1668)
    Includes aerial view of NW waterfront, Guild's Lake Area, railroad lines
  - SE Neighborhoods- Miscellaneous [including Buckman], 1923-1940 (Folder 1670)
    Includes SE Morrison St., SE 66th and Foster Rd, SE 28th Ave., SE Woodstock Ave., radiator store on SE 7th Ave, roadwork on SE 2nd Ave and Morrison, SE Belmont storefronts and residences
  - SE Neighborhoods-Arleta (SE 15), 1923-1929 (Folder 1671)
    Includes SE Foster Rd. storefronts and residences,
  - SE Neighborhoods-East Portland (SE1, NE1), Undated (Folder 1673)
    SE Grand Ave storefronts and residences, Union Ave,
  - SE Neighborhoods-East Portland, Undated (Folder 1673)
    Includes trolley tracks and lines, industrial areas, churches, roadwork on SE Morrison and 10th
  - SE Neighborhoods-Lents (SE 16), 1939 (Folder 1674)
    Undeveloped land at SE Cora and 92nd
  - SE Neighborhoods-Montavilla and Mount Tabor, 1938 (Folder 1675)
    Includes images of farm land on SE 92nd, construction on SE 55th and Hawthorne, laborer posing by large stones on SE 55th
  - SE Neighborhoods-Sellwood, 1935-1938 (Folder 1677)
    Includes residential houses on SE 17th Ave
  - SE Neighborhoods-Sunnyside including Ladd's Addition, 1913-1941 (Folder 1678)
    Includes SE Belmont, SE Grand Ave, SE Powell, SE 20th and Oak, east side trolley tracks and lines, collapsing house on SE 28th and Clinton, residential corner markets, streetcar on SE 33rd and Belmont, undeveloped land, barn and farm land on SE Center St.
  - SE/NE Union Ave (now Martin Luther King Jr.Blvd), Undated (Folder 1679)
    Includes images of streetcar in motion, corner gas stations, demolished building on NE Union and Burnside, Egyptian Theatre, images of railroad track laying
  - SE/NE 82nd Ave, 1932-1939 (Folder 1679-A)
    Includes images of NE Sandy, barracks on NE 82nd, truck accident on SE 82nd and Foster, roadwork and laborers
  - NE Neighborhoods-Miscellaneous, 1936 (Folder 1680)
    Includes images of NE 19th and Glisan, NE Siskiyou, future site of Memorial Colliseum
  - NE Neighborhood- Beaumont, 1935 (Folder 1681)
    Residential houses on NE 39th Ave.
  - NE Neighborhoods-Hollywood, 1934-1939 (Folder 1683)
    Includes corner markets, residential houses, exteriors images of the Hollywood Theatre
  - NE Neighborhoods-Irvington, 1938 (Folder 1684)
    Includes images of NE Broadway, residential streets, east side trolley tracks and lines
  - NE Neighborhoods-Laurelhurst, 1934-1941 (Folder 1685)
    Includes images of residential streets, Sullivan's gulch, shanty town shacks
  - NE Neighborhoods-Parkrose, 1939 (Folder 1687)
    Residential streets
  - N. Neighborhoods-Miscellaneous (including Hayden Island), 1923-1939 (Folder 1690)
    Includes images of the Columbia Slough at high and low tide, work crews clearing the Columbia Slough South Channel, Balch Gulch, North Interstate Ave., exterior of Grigsby Bros. box manufacture
  - N. Neighborhoods- Albina, 1934-1938 (Folder 1691)
    Includes images of construction on N. Interstate and Thompson, residential houses on Union Ave., stretches of Interstate Ave., intersection of Flint and Russell
  - N. Neighborhoods-Kenton, 1931 (Folder 1694)
    Includes images of residential houses, farm land and railroad lines on N. Lombard St.
  - N. Neighborhoods-St. John's, 1921-1944 (Folder 1698)
    Includes images of residential houses, undeveloped land, interior and exterior shots of burned building on N. Columbia Blvd.
  - N. Neighborhoods-Swan Island, Undated (Folder 1699)
    Images of gravel road leading to Swan Island access
  - Bridges-Miscellaneous-Bridges and Viaducts, 1923-1938 (Folder 1700-A)
    Includes images of viaduct on NE 12th, Ford St. Bridge spanning Jefferson St., visualization of the proposed Vista Avenue viaduct, Vista St. Bridge, series of images of NE 33rd viaduct including construction of, Alexandra Ave. bridge construction, construction of Vancouver Ave. viaduct, construction of bridge on NW Italian Way, Incinerator Bridge, damaged column of NW Lovejoy on-ramp, illustration of proposed SE 17th Ave viaduct, Grand Avenue bridge construction, Burlingame Bridge construction
  - Bridges-St. John's Bridge, Undated (Folder 1701)
    Includes image of model for St. John's bridge
  - Bridges-Broadway Bridge, 1929-1936 (Folder 1703)
    Includes image of subway stairs leading from bridge to Union Station, bridge raised for passage of ship, aerial image showing future site of Memorial Coliseum
  - Bridges- Steel/Railroad Bridge, 1931 (Folder 1704)
    Includes image of model for bridge
  - Bridges-Morrison Bridge, 1924 (Folder 1706)
  - Bridges-Madison/Hawthorne Bridge, Undated (Folder 1707)
  - Bridges-Ross Island Bridge, 1927 (Folder 1709)
    Image series of bridge construction on southwest side of Willamette River
  - Bridges-Sellwood Bridge, 1926 (Folder 1710)
  - Bridges-Johnson Creek Bridges, 1926 (Folder 1711)
    Images of damaged bridge road
  - 1720, Undated (Folder Business Firms-A)
    Images of Portland area business exteriors and signs
  - Business Firms- B, Undated (Folder 1721)
    Images of Portland area business building exteriors
  - Business Firms-Ca-Col, Undated (Folder 1723)
  - Business Firms- Com-Cz, Undated (Folder 1723-A)
    Images of Portland area business and signs
  - Business Firms- D, 1929-1934 (Folder 1724)
  - Business Firms-E, Undated (Folder 1725)
  - Business Firms-F, Undated (Folder 1726)
  - Business Firms-G, 1929 (Folder 1727)
  - Business Firms-H, Undated (Folder 1729)
    Images of Portland area business exteriors and signs, includes series of images showing inspection of businesses by health inspector
  - Business Firms- I, Undated (Folder 1730)
  - Business Firms-J, Undated (Folder 1731)
  - Business Firms- K [except Kaiser Shipyards], 1929-1942 (Folder 1732)
  - Business Firms-L, Undated (Folder 1733)
  - Business Firms -M, Undated (Folder 1734)
  - Business Firms-N, 1927-1929 (Folder 1735)
  - Business Firms-O [Except Oregon Shipbuilding Corportation], Undated (Folder 1736)
  - Business Firms-P-Q [Except "Pacific", "Portland" and Parrish Watkins Real Estate], 1929-1933 (Folder 1737)
    Business Firms-P-Q [Except "Pacific", "Portland" and Parrish Watkins Real Estate]
  - Business Firms- "Portland", 1934-1940 (Folder 1737-B)
    Images of Portland area business exteriors and signs, includes images of city auditor's office and storage files, interior and exterior of Public Employment Bureau
  - Business Firms-R, 1929-1394 (Folder 1742)
  - Business Firms- S, 1927-1929 (Folder 1744)
  - Business Firms- Saloons and Bars, Undated (Folder 1745)
  - Business Firms- T, Undated (Folder 1746)
  - Business Firms-U, Undated (Folder 1747)
  - Business Firms-V, 1923-1938 (Folder 1748)
  - Business Firms-W, Undated (Folder 1749)
  - Business Firms- Willamette Iron and Steel Co., Undated (Folder 1750)
  - Business Firms-X-Y-Z and miscellaneous, Undated (Folder 1752)
    Images of Portland area business exteriors and signs, includes images of junk dealers and wares on downtown streets
  - Buildings-A, Undated (Folder 1755)
    Includes images of motor vehicle inspection station
  - Buildings- Apartments unidentified, Undated (Folder 1756)
    Images of apartment building facades
  - Buildings- Apartments A-M, 1929 (Folder 1757)
  - Buildings- B [except Banks], Undated (Folder 1761)
    Images of barns on SE Bybee Ave
  - Buildings-Banks-Miscellaneous, Undated (Folder 1762)
    Exterior image of the Geo W. Bates Bank
  - Buildings-Churches-Miscellaneous, 1924-1930 (Folder 1768)
  - Buildings-Churches-Catholic, Undated (Folder 1770)
  - Buildings-Churches-Methodist, Undated (Folder 1776)
  - Buildings-Churches-Presbyterian, Undated (Folder 1777)
  - Buildings-Churches-Salvation Army, Undated (Folder 1777.7)
  - Buildings-City Hall, 1935-1943 (Folder 1780)
    Contains image of Christmas tree in lobby; image of condemned electrical plugs
  - Buildings-Fraternal Orders and Clubs, 1935 (Folder 1786)
    Images of sidewalk outside SW Irvington Club
  - Buildings- Fraternal Orders and Clubs-Masonic Temple, 1872 (Folder 1790)
    Postcard image of the dedication of the hall
  - Buildings- Fraternal Orders and Clubs- Multnomah Athletic Club, Undated (Folder 1790.1)
  - Buildings- G, 1929-1933 (Folder 1792)
  - Buildings- Hospitals- Miscellaneous, 1937-1938 (Folder 1794)
    Includes images of Isolation Hospital, interior images of hospital department, staff and patients, images of patients recieving iron lung treatment, images of vaccination clinics
  - Buildings- Hospitals- St.Vincent, 1931 (Folder 1797)
    Images of mudslide on hospital grounds
  - Buildings- Hotels A-B, Undated (Folder 1798-A)
  - Buildings-Hotels-C (Folder 1798-B)
  - Buildings-Hotels-D-H, Undated (Folder 1798-C)
  - Buildings- Hotels-I-L, 1940 (Folder 1798-E)
  - Buildings-Hotels-M-P, Undated (Folder 1799-B)
    1800
  - Buildings-Hotels-Multnomah Hotel, Undated (Folder 1800)
  - Buildings-Hotels-T-Z and unidentified, Undated (Folder 1801-C)
  - Buildings-I-K, 1933 (Folder 1802)
    Includes images of incinerators
  - Buildings-L, 1933 (Folder 1803)
  - Buildings-M, Undated (Folder 1806)
  - Buildings-P-Q, 1928 (Folder 1810)
    Images of Municipal Paving Plant
  - Buildings-Pioneer Post Office and Pioneer Court House, 1934 (Folder 1811)
    Includes images of the Public Employment Office, image of a group of unemployed draftsman, interior of auditor's office
  - Buildings-Public Market Building, 1937 (Folder 1812)
    Includes images of produce and flower stands
  - Buildings-Residences-Unidentified, Undated (Folder 1814 Folder 1)
    Exterior images of residences on E. Burnside
  - Buildings-Residences-Unidentified, 1929-1942 (Folder 1814 Folder 2)
  - Buildings-Residences-S, 1940 (Folder 1830)
    Residence of Meton Smith
  - Buildings-S, Undated (Folder 1834)
  - Buildings-Schools-A-B, Undated (Folder 1835)
    Includes images of Benson High School
  - Buildings-Schools-X-Z and Miscellaneous, Undated (Folder 1857)
    Image of unidentified public school
  - Buildings-Theatres-Miscellaneous, Undated (Folder 1860)
    Exterior image of Seller's Theatre
  - Buildings-Union Station, 1913 (Folder 1872)
  - Buildings-W, Undated (Folder 1873)
    Images of Weatherly Building exterior
  - Buildings-X-Z, Undated (Folder 1874)
    Images of the YMCA on NE Sandy Blvd.
  - Buildings-Unidentified, Miscellaneous and Architectural Details, 1929-1937 (Folder 1875)
    Includes interior images of public restrooms
  - Miscellaneous-Advertising and Billboards, Undated (Folder 1878)
  - Miscellaneous-Amusement Parks-The Oaks, 1931 (Folder 1879-A)
    Images of land prior to construction of Oaks Park
  - Miscellaneous-Amusement Parks-Council Crest, 1937 (Folder 1879-B)
  - Miscellaneous-Cemeteries, 1928-1939 (Folder 1880)
    Includes images of Lone Fir Cemetery, construction of Mt. Scott Cemetery
  - Miscellaneous-Fire Department-Miscellaneous, 1930-1938 (Folder 1881)
    Includes images of fire boats in action, firemen performing fire tower drill, incinerators
  - Miscellaneous-Fire Department-Engines, 1939-1945 (Folder 1883)
    Images of fire department vehicles
  - Miscellaneous-Fire Department-Fire Houses, 1944 (Folder 1885)
    Images of fire alarm boxes
  - Miscellaneous-Fire Department-Parades and Bands, 1944 (Folder 1886)
    Includes images of "Miss Flame" performing at function
  - Miscellaneous-Fountains, 1938 (Folder 1888-A)
    Image of public drinking fountain
  - Miscellaneous-Statues, Monuments Memorials, Undated (Folder 1888-B)
  - Miscellaneous-Parks-A-M, 1932-1933 (Folder 1890)
    Includes image of model for a proposed park and Civic Center
  - Miscellaneous-Parks-N-Z, 1935 (Folder 1891)
    Includes images of Parks Department mowing machines, public swimming pools, gym classes, image of pottery club meeting at Peninsula Park
  - Miscellaneous-Parks-Golf Courses, 1934 (Folder 1893.5)
  - Miscellaneous-Public Works-Miscellaneous, 1924-1939 (Folder 1898)
    Includes images of Columbia Slough drainage gate
  - Miscellaneous-Public Works-Sewers, 1926-1941 (Folder 1899)
    Includes aerial image of sewage treatment plant, images of sewer construction and repair on various streets, photographs of sewer expenditure graphs
  - Miscellaneous-Public Works-Street Clearing, 1937 (Folder 1900)
    Image of snow plow at work
  - Miscellaneous-Public Works-Street Repairing, 1922-1942 (Folder 1901)
    Includes exterior images of the Municipal Paving Plant, downtown road repair near the Steel Bridge, street repair project in Ladd's Addition, roadwork on SE Caruther's and SE 8th showing team of horses at work, images of paving and grading machines, road repair on Union Ave
  - Miscellaneous-Public Works-Water Supply, 1927-1939 (Folder 1902)
    Includes image of Water Department Personnel, water testing machine, Balch Gulch intake project, images of creek at Wichita Station, construction on Hermosa St. drain, laying of Bull Run pipeline
  - Miscellaneous-Transportation-Miscellaneous, 1923-1944 (Folder 1903)
    Includes images of railroad crossing at SE 2nd and SE Morrison, interior and exterior images of the Motor Vehicle Inspection building on SE Powell Blvd. and Milwaukie Blvd. including aeiral shot, images of vehicle inspection and inspectors at work, the Titania on the Willamette river, images of the Portland Flying Service airplanes and preparation for flight
  - Miscellaneous-Transportation-Buses, 1933-1944 (Folder 1908)
    Includes images of Union Pacific Stages buses and depot on SW Salmon, images of Greyhound station
  - 1909, 1936
    Image of men at unidentified station yard
  - Community Activities-Miscellaneous, 1922-1936 (Folder 1917)
    Includes images of ambulance boat on Columbia River, bomb shelter siren, images of city and county "Clean Up" project including advertising billboards, images of community performances, Milk Fund football team practice, children participating in Milk Fund program
  - Community Activities-Parades, 1927 (Folder 1918)
    Images of the Public Works Rose Festival Float
  - Community Activies-Bands, Orchestras, 1935 (Folder 1919)
    Images of community performances at Powell Park
  - Maps-General, 1927 (Folder 1924-A)
    Images of maps, graphs and statistics created by the Department of Public Works